### Stanislau Beliasau

New York, 11229



bestasoff.github.io +1-347-992-8886







Eligible to work in the United States - Green Card holder. Middle Machine Learning Engineer with about 2 years of hands-on experience in machine learning projects (mainly in Computer Vision and NLP). Have experience working with Large Language models and their training and optimization. Have a strong background in CNNs, ViTs, GANs, and Diffusion models (like Stable diffusion, its applications, and downstream tasks).

#### Skills

**Programming languages**: Python, C++.

Frameworks: PyTorch, torch.distributed, torchlightning, huggingface, FastAPI, Flask, scikit-learn, OpenCV, numpy, pandas, catboost, xgboost, coreml, bitsandbytes.

Machine Learning: Computer Vision, NLP, classical ML, distributed training, data-parallel training, model-parallel training, model deployment, model distillation, model compression, memory footprint reduction.

Tools: docker, docker-compose, git, Kubernetes, Airflow, Prometheus, gRPC, TensorRT, ONNX.

### Work Experience

# Gradient & Persona: AI Photo & Video mobile editors, New York, Remote

Middle Computer Vision Engineer

Aug. 2022 – Present.

- Make massive research on image generation, especially with Stable Diffusion model. Played a crucial role in developing the brand-new encoding method into its latent space.
- Run experiments with different Stable Diffusion downstream tasks like custom fine-tuning, introducing new modules, curating task-specific datasets, and implementing papers—accelerated image generation by 30%.
- Generate and curate custom datasets. Use CLIP, BLIP, StyleGAN, pix2pix models for processings. Resulted in obtaining datasets that helped to train new models.
- o Train brand-new re-aging img2img filters both server and real-time.
- Train new versions of image-warping body-tune models both for images and videos and lightweight body segmentation models. Resulted in better postprocessing on inference.
- Train dozens of new beauty filters, and develop new loss functions for training. Resulted in a better quality of model outputs.
- Making GANs work in real-time on mobile devices with HD quality, 60fps and taking less than 2 MB.
- Deploy models both on IOS and server using torch.jit and coreml.

### ArtLabs, Minsk, Belarus, Remote

Machine Learning Engineer

*May.* 2022 – *Aug.* 2022

- Created and curated custom datasets from unstructured client data using Pandas and SQL.
- Trained numerous time-series models for demand forecasting, reducing forecast MAPE by 20%.
- Developed API for the model using FastAPI.
- o Constructed production pipelines with AirFlow to convert raw data into a feature vector, feed it into the model, and forecast the product demand.

#### Yandex School of Data analysis, Minsk, Belarus

ML course tutor assistant

Feb. 2022 - May. 2022

- Gave several lectures on machine learning: including an introduction to NLP and CV.
- Conducted seminars and checked homework.

## iTechArt, Minsk, Belarus

Machine Learning Engineer

Feb. 2022 – Aug. 2022

o Developed gRPC endpoint client/server image classification service with FastAPI framework using Uvicorn and Prometheus with Docker and Supervisord. The endpoint was designed to asynchronically process client requests for classification and return the responses to a client.

🚺 Yandex, Minsk, Belarus

Software Engineer Intern

*May.* 2021 – Nov. 2021

- Developed rule-based and NLP-based solutions for affiliations parsing.
- Developed a data annotation service using Flask framework. Wrapped it into Docker and deployed it to the server.

#### Education

### 🌺 Yandex School of Data analysis, Moscow, Russia

Master's degree level Machine Learning developer academic program

Sep. 2020 – June. 2022

o YSDA has become Russia's leading data analysis program with a nearly 5% admission rate. Its courses are the foundation for Master's programs at major universities, such as the Higher School of Economics and MIPT.

Belarusian State University, Minsk, Belarus Bachelor of Computer Science

Sep. 2018 - Aug. 2022

Awarded a full scholarship and stipend by the government per entrance exam results.